Guide to the Mick Moloney Irish-American Music and Popular Culture Field Recordings AIA.031.002
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I: Private Performances, 1970-1992, circa 1970-Jan 27, 1992
  - Unidentified. Labeled "It's a Great Day for the Irish." aiamm648R, undated; aiamm648R (Box 75)
    This film reel has not been digitized and there is no access copy available. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. These requests are free of charge and can be made in anticipation of your visit. The process typically takes four to six weeks. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A librarian will respond to you with further information.
  - Unidentified. Labeled "Kids in Bridesbury - Eugene's Kids." Interview with little boys about King Arthur and street games and with some women about Polish Easter traditions and Polish-Irish relations in the neighborhood. (Length: 01:30:00) aiamm823C, Feb 17, 1974; aiamm823C (Box 48, Box 25)
  - Unidentified. Labeled "Louie Quinn - Kelly's Reel" Private trio performances of accordion, fiddle and piano. Handwritten note on box: "Tom, I put a paper in the tape where the tune starts. Just give it to Lou he will understand." (Length: 02:00:00). aiamm448R, undated; aiamm448R (Box 15, Box 38)
  - Unidentified. Labeled "Mandolin." aiamm1467C, undated; aiamm1467C (Box 45, Box 69)
  - Unidentified. Labeled "Master Out - Takes." aiamm449R, undated; aiamm449R (Box 18, Box 48)
  - Unidentified. Labeled "Matty Ryan et al." aiamm642R, undated; aiamm642R (Box 75, Box 67)
  - Unidentified. Labeled "Maureen Tunes." aiamm1447C, undated; aiamm1447C (Box 44, Box 66)
  - Unidentified. Labeled "Mick." aiamm1389C, undated; aiamm1389C (Box 71, Box 44)
  - Unidentified. Labeled "Mick Set." aiamm1413C, undated; aiamm1413C (Box 44, Box 70)
  - Unidentified. Labeled "Mrs. Micho Russell...Willie Clancy and John Kelly." aiamm646R, Jul 25, 1969; aiamm646R (Box 75, Box 69)
  - Unidentified. Labeled "Norwegian Language." aiamm1435C, undated; aiamm1435C (Box 69, Box 44)
  - Unidentified. Labeled "Nova / British Isles." aiamm1382C, undated; aiamm1382C (Box 71, Box 44)
  - Unidentified. Labeled "Och's Tape of Old Pipers." aiamm1475C, undated; aiamm1475C (Box 69, Box 45)
  - Unidentified: Labeled "Old 78s." aiamm1395C, undated; aiamm1395C (Box 44, Box 70)
  - Unidentified. Labeled "Old 78s." aiamm1497C, undated; aiamm1497C (Box 73, Box 45)
  - Unidentified. Labeled "Old 78s (S. Egan)." aiamm1493C, undated; aiamm1493C (Box 73, Box 45)
  - Unidentified. Labeled "Old 78s to Learn." aiamm1471C, undated; aiamm1471C (Box 72, Box 45)
  - Unidentified. Labeled "Orange..." aiamm1440C, undated; aiamm1440C (Box 44, Box 73)
  - Unidentified. Labeled "Ottowa CH40." aiamm1446C, undated; aiamm1446C (Box 44, Box 70)
  - Unidentified. Labeled "Peggy Keegan First Verses." aiamm649R, undated; aiamm649R (Box 69, Box 75)
  - Unidentified. Labeled "Roses Record Instrumentals." aiamm1441C, undated; aiamm1441C (Box 72, Box 44)
  - Unidentified. Labeled "Rough Basic Tracks." aiamm1371C, undated; aiamm1371C (Box 71, Box 44)
  - Unidentified. Labeled "Self." aiamm1434C, undated; aiamm1434C (Box 73, Box 44)
  - Unidentified. Labeled "Self K. Keane." aiamm1469C, Nov 20, 1997; aiamm1469C (Box 45, Box 70)
  - Unidentified. Labeled "Singers Club." aiamm650R, 1967; aiamm650R (Box 75, Box 68)
  - Unidentified. Labeled "Songs and Music, Tyrone." A fiddler plays for another Tyrone man with some chat followed by many songs from various singers. Probably not recorded by Moloney. (Length: 01:30:00) aiamm828C, undated; aiamm828C (Box 25, Box 48)
  - Unidentified. Labeled "Songs and Tunes to Learn." aiamm1408C, undated; aiamm1408C (Box 44, Box 70)
  - Unidentified. Labeled "Songs and Tunes to Learn." aiamm1332C, Jan 1982; aiamm1332C (Box 71, Box 44)
  - Unidentified. Labeled "Standard World's Fair." aiamm1481C, undated; aiamm1481C (Box 72, Box 45)
  - Unidentified. Labeled "Tape 2: Banjo Mandolin Record." aiamm628R, Jul 3, 1980; aiamm628R (Box 67, Box 75)
  - Unidentified. Labeled "Tape 4: Banjo Mandolin Record." aiamm627R, Jul 7, 1980; aiamm627R (Box 67, Box 75)
  - Unidentified. Labeled "Tape I for Class II." aiamm1472C, undated; aiamm14 (Box 45, Box 72)
  - Unidentified. Labeled "Tara Summer 1974." aiamm1463C, aiamm1463C (Box 45, Box 72)
  - Unidentified. Labeled "Thai Songs and Own Tunes." aiamm1454C, undated; aiamm1454C (Box 72, Box 45)
  - Unidentified. Labeled "Time Marks Time - Perfect Copy." aiamm450R, undated; aiamm450R (Box 18, Box 48)
  - Unidentified. Labeled "Tribute to Mick M." aiamm1451C, undated; aiamm1451C (Box 44, Box 69)
  - Unidentified. Labeled "Tunes." aiamm1449C, undated; aiamm1449C (Box 44, Box 69)
  - Unidentified. Labeled "Tunes for Mick - Mike Seeger." aiamm1323C, undated; aiamm1323C (Box 73, Box 44)
  - Unidentified. Labeled "Tunes for Tour." aiamm1473C, undated; aiamm1473C (Box 72, Box 45)
  - Unidentified. Labeled "Tunes to Learn." aiamm829C, undated; aiamm829C (Box 27, Box 48)
  - Unidentified. Labeled "Tunes to Learn." aiamm1421C, Aug 1985; aiamm1421C (Box 70, Box 44)
  - Unidentified. Labeled "Tunes to Learn." aiamm1377C, 1986; aiamm1377C (Box 44, Box 71)
  - Unidentified. Labeled "Unknown Singer, Self, Avondale." aiamm637R, undated; aiamm637R (Box 67, Box 75)
  - Unidentified. Private performance of "Jesse Winch's Jig" and "Tom Doherty's Polka" and a waltz on unaccompanied melodeon. (Length: 00:10:00) aiamm830C, undated; aiamm830C (Box 25, Box 48)
  - Unidentified. Unlabeled. aiamm1437C, undated; aiamm1437C (Box 69, Box 44)
  - Unidentified. Unlabeled. aiamm630R, undated; aiamm630R (Box 75, Box 67)
  - Unidentified. Unlabeled. aiamm631R, undated; aiamm631R (Box 75, Box 67)
  - Unidentified. Unlabeled. aiamm634R, undated; aiamm634R (Box 75, Box 67)
  - Unidentified. Unlabeled. aiamm635R, undated; aiamm635R (Box 75, Box 67)
  - Unidentified. Unlabeled. aiamm636R, undated; aiamm636R (Box 67, Box 75)
  - Unidentified. Unlabeled. aiamm639R, undated; aiamm639R (Box 75, Item aiamm639R)
    No content - reel contains only leader.
  - Unidentified. Unlabeled. aiamm644R, undated; aiamm644R (Box 75)
  - Unidentified. Unlabeled. aiamm647R, undated; aiamm647R (Box 75, Box 68)
  - Unidentified. Unlabeled. aiamm651R, undated; aiamm651R (Box 76, Box 68)
  - Unidentified. Unlabeled. aiamm652R, undated; aiamm652R (Box 76, Box 68)
  - Unidentified. Unlabeled. aiamm653R, undated; aiamm653R (Box 76, Box 69)
  - Unidentified. Unlabeled. aiamm12CD, undated; aiamm12CD (Box 74, Box 76)
  - Up South: Dance Demos. aiamm17CD, undated; aiamm17CD (Box 76, Box 74)
  - Various artists. Compilation tape of private performances and commercial recordings. Musicians include: Hamper McBee (songs and stories), Eugene O'Donnell (fiddle), Billy McComiskey (accordion), Mick Moloney (banjo), Martin O'Connor (accordion) playing tunes and a short excerpt from a big session. (Total length: 00:45:00). aiamm834C, Aug, 1982; aiamm834C (Box 38, Box 25)
  - Various Artists, including Maureen Fitzpatrick, Martin Mulvihill, Maeve Donnelly, Liz Carroll, Mick Moloney, Tony De Marco, Eugene O'Donnell, Paddy Cronin, Lewis Quinn, Tim Britton, and Ed Reavy. aiamm620R, undated; aiamm620R (Box 75, Box 67)
  - Various artists. Interviews at the New York Fleadh with Patty Conway (accordion) and John Ivers (Eileen's father) about competition (20 minutes, Apr 1978); private performance by Dawn Mulvihill (whistle) (10 minutes, Apr 1978); interview with Michael Deeley about Irish music in San Francisco, CA. (10 minutes, Aug 11, 1978); noisy session including Mick Moloney, Eugene O'Donnell and unidentified accordion (5 minutes); interview in Los Angeles with Howard and Roz Lerman (radio show hosts) about interest in Irish music in Los Angeles (15 minutes, Aug 13, 1978). (Total length: 01:00:00). aiamm833C, Apr, 1978 and Aug 11, 1978; aiamm833C (Box 25, Box 38)
  - Various Artists. Labeled "20 Examples of Shay Healy." aiamm25CD, undated; aiamm25CD (Box 76, Box 74)
  - Various Artists. Labeled "Aer Lingus In-Flight Milwaukee Irish Fest, Harry Bradshaw - Producer." aiamm18CD, Mar 1997; aiamm18CD (Box 76, Box 74)
  - Various Artists. Labeled "Celtic on Modern American Music: Accompanying CD." aiamm8CD, undated; aiamm8CD (Box 76, Box 74)
  - Various Artists. Labeled "Great Day for the Irish" (Thomas O'Brien, Anne Greehoy, Danny Kiernan, Bill Rempell). aiamm1496C, undated; aiamm1496C (Box 73, Box 45)
  - Various Artists. Labeled "Heroes and Martyrs in Irish Song Traditions." aiamm1458C, undated; aiamm1458C (Box 72, Box 45)
  - Various Artists. Labeled "Irish 78 RPMs from the Collection of Michael Stoner, Tape 2." aiamm623R, undated; aiamm623R (Box 67, Box 75)
  - Various Artists. Labeled "Irish 78 RPMs from the Collection of Michael Stoner, Tape 3." aiamm611R, undated; aiamm611R (Box 67, Box 45)
  - Various Artists. Labeled "Irish 78 RPMs from the Collection of Michael Stoner, Tape 4." aiamm613R, undated; aiamm613R (Box 69, Box 45)
  - Various Artists. Labeled "Irish Music: Early Recordings" (Patrick Fitzpatrick, Michael Gallagher, Edward Mullaney, Joe Sullivan, Willie Clancy, Sean Dempsey, James Ennis, Philip Martin, Tommy Reck, Leo Rowsome, Liam Walsh) aiamm1316C, undated; aiamm1316C (Box 44, Box 65)
  - Various Artists. Labeled "Irish Music: Early Recordings: Pipers." aiamm1415C, Dec 4, 1987; aiamm1415C (Box 70, Box 44)
  - Various Artists. Labeled "Irish Music in the Civil War." aiamm1340C, undated; aiamm1340C (Box 44, Box 73)
  - Various Artists. Labeled "Irish Music in the Civil War." aiamm1321C, undated; aiamm1321C (Box 73, Box 44)
  - Various Artists. Labeled "Mick Moloney Ref Mix 2." aiamm19CD, undated; aiamm19CD (Box 76, Box 74)
  - Various Artists. Labeled "Old 78s: Gaffney, Ennis, Kimmel, Conlon, and Unknown Banjo." aiamm1419C, undate; aiamm1419C (Box 73, Box 44)
  - Various Artists. Labeled "Old Timey Music Rec. by Blanton Owen and Others: Tommy Jarrell, Fred Cockenham." aiamm452R, undated; aiamm452R (Box 18, Box 48)
  - Various Artists. Labeled "Tape I Sent to Smithsonian." Moloney introduces excerpts of private performances by Andy McGann and Paddy Reynolds (fiddles), Jack Coen (flute) and Fr. Charlie Coen (concertina), Mike Rafferty (flute), Mike Preston (flute) and Anne McIlvaney (piano), James Keane (accordion), Mike Flynn (flute), Sean McGlynn (accordion), Maureen Glynn (piano), Johnny Cronin (fiddle), Gene Kelly (accordion) and James Mahon (piano), Liz Carroll (fiddle), Jimmy Keane (accordion), Seamus Cooley (flute), Johnny McGreevy (fiddle), Joe Shannon (uilleann pipes). (Length: 01:00:00). aiamm831C, 1976; aiamm831C (Box 38, Box 83, Audiocassette aiamm831C)
  - Various Artists. Labeled "Tape II Sent to Smithsonian." Moloney introduces excerpts of private performances by himself, Michael Flatley (flute), L.E. McCullough (whistle), James Keane Sr. (vocals), Mary Cooley (vocals), Joe Heaney (vocals). (Length: 00:30:00) aiamm832C, 1976; aiamm832C (Box 83, Audiocassette aiamm832C, Box 38)
  - Various Artists. Labeled "Re-recorded 78 RPMs." aiamm596R, undated; aiamm596R (Box 66, Box 45)
  - Various Artists. Labeled "Re-recorded 78 RPMs." aiamm615R, undated; aiamm615R (Box 75, Box 67)
  - Various Artists. Labeled "Re-recorded 78s." aiamm622R, Apr 1977; aiamm622R (Box 68, Box 75)
  - Various Artists. Labeled "Re-recorded 78s (Reel 10)." aiamm607R, May 1977; aiamm607R (Box 45, Box 66)
  - Various Artists. Labeled "Re-recorded 78 RPM Records (Tape A)." aiamm601R, Feb 26, 1976; aiamm601R (Box 69, Box 45)
  - Various Artists. Labeled "Re-recorded 78 RPM Records (Tape B)." aiamm608R, Feb 21, 1976; aiamm608R (Box 45, Box 66)
  - Various Artists. Labeled "Re-recorded 78s (Columbia) (Tape 1)." aiamm602R, Apr 14, 1977; aiamm602R (Box 45, Box 66)
  - Various Artists. Labeled "Re-recorded 78s (Columbia) (Tape 2)." aiamm606R, Apr 14, 1977; aiamm606R (Box 66, Box 45)
  - Various Artists. Labeled "Re-recorded 78s (Tape 3)." aiamm597R, undated; aiamm597R (Box 66, Box 45)
  - Various Artists. Labeled "Re-recorded 78s (Tape 4)." aiamm605R, undated; aiamm605R (Box 45, Box 66)
  - Various Artists. Labeled "Re-recorded 78s (Tape 9)." aiamm594R, undated; aiamm594R (Box 66, Box 45)
  - Various Artists. Labeled "Re-recorded 78s (Tape 11)." aiamm595R, undated; aiamm595R (Box 66, Box 45)
  - Various Artists. Labeled "Re-recorded 78s from Kay Tuohy's Collection" (Tape 12). aiamm603R, May 1977; aiamm603R (Box 45, Box 66)
  - Various Artists. Labeled "Re-recorded 78s from May Mullins' Collection (Tape 6)." aiamm621R, May 1977; aiamm621R (Box 67, Box 75)
  - Various Artists. Labeled "Re-recorded 78s from May Mullins' Collection (Tape 7)." aiamm609R, May 1977; aiamm609R (Box 67, Box 45)
  - Various Artists. Labeled "Re-recorded 78s (from May Mullins' Collection) (Tape 8)." aiamm614R, May 1977; aiamm614R (Box 45, Box 67)
  - Various Artists. Labeled "Re-recorded 78s (from Mary's Records) (Columbia) (Tape 3)." aiamm593R, Apr 14, 1977; aiamm593R (Box 70, Box 45)
  - Various Artists. Labeled "Rounder Wind Instruments Record." aiamm835C, undated; aiamm835C (Box 56, Box 27)
  - Various Artists. Labeled "Trip to Brittany Disc #1." aiamm7CD, Aug 2001; aiamm7CD (Box 76, Box 79)
  - Various Artists. Labeled "Trip to Brittany Disc #2." aiamm6CD, Aug 2001; aiamm6CD (Box 79, Box 76)
  - Various Artists. Labeled "UL 2002." aiamm1423C, undated; aiamm1423C (Box 73, Box 44)
  - Various Artists. Private performance by Jerry O'Sullivan (uilleann pipes) (15 minutes); Concert performance by Moloney (banjo, guitar), James Keane (accordion), Sean Keane (fiddle) (30 minutes). (Length: 00:45:00) aiamm1231C, undated; aiamm1231C (Box 64, Box 26)
  - Various Artists. Side A: Private performance by the Kilfenora Ceili Band, Ennis Co Clare; Side B: Music from Gussie O'Connor's Pub, Doolin. Session with Micho (whistle) and Packie Russell (concertina) and Moloney (guitar). (Length: 01:30:00). aiamm1232C, Jan 4, 1974; aiamm1232C (Box 41, Box 26)
  - Various Artists. Side A: Private performance by Brendan Mulvihill (fiddle), Martin Mulvihill (fiddle), Mick Moloney (guitar) in the Bronx. (20 minutes); Private performances by Mick Moloney (banjo), Timmy Britton (pipes, whistle) in Philadelphia; Side B: Moloney practices banjo and experiments with some homemade guitar overdubs. (30 minutes). (Length: 01:15:00) aiamm1228C, Jul 8, 1980; aiamm1228C (Box 26, Box 64)
  - Vesey, John (fiddle) Interview at Vesey's home in Philadelphia, PA. The Sligo fiddler discusses his life and music. (Length: 01:30:00). aiamm836C, Jan 8, 1977; aiamm836C (Box 83, Audiocassette aiamm836C, Box 38)
  - Vesey, John (fiddle), Flynn, Joe (fiddle) Private performance of solos and duets including some unidentified whistle (35 minutes); pub performance by Johnny Cronin (fiddle) and unidentified guitar and singer (20 minutes); private performance by Martin Mulvihill (fiddle) with unidentified guitar (5 minutes). (Total length: 01:00:00) aiamm837C, undated; aiamm837C (Box 25, Box 48)
  - Walsh, John (banjo) Interview and private performance in Wasilla, AK. Dublin-born promoter and musician discusses his life and music intersperced with tunes (45 minutes) followed by Moloney practicing tunes on mandolin (10 minutes) (Total length: 00:50:00) aiamm838C, undated; aiamm838C (Box 48, Box 25)
  - Whelan, John (accordion), Carroll, Liz (fiddle) Poor fidelity recording of a concert performance by Carroll with unidentified guitar and percussion, later joined by Billy McComiskey (accordion) followed by ten minutes of John Whelan putting tunes on tape at several speeds. (Total length: 01:10:00) aiamm839C, undated; aiamm839C (Box 48, Box 25)
  - Wick, Linnane (dancer) Homemade recording of step dancing to commercial fiddle and piano music. (Length: 00:05:00) aiamm840C, undated; aiamm840C (Box 48, Box 25)
  - Wick, Regan (synthesizer) Demo arrangements of tunes. (Length: 00:10:00) aiamm841C, undated; aiamm841C (Box 48, Box 25)
  - Wild Geese (group) Rough mixes from Windmill Lane Studios, Dublin for the album In Full Flight. Musicians include: Manus Lunny, Gerry (banjo) O'Connor. (Length: 00:45:00) aiamm842C, 1983; aiamm842C (Box 25, Box 48)
  - Wildcats (group) Old-time music demo featuring fiddle, bango, guitar, male and female vocals. (Length: 00:15:00) aiamm843C, 1987; aiamm843C (Box 48, Box 25)
  - Wilkinson, Dessie (flute, vocals), Moloney, Mick (guitar, mandolin) Private performance at Moloney's home, Philadelphia, PA. (Length: 00:30:00). aiamm844C, Jul 7, 1981; aiamm844C (Box 83, Audiocassette aiamm844C, Box 38)
  - Williams, William A. "'Twas Only an Irishman's Dream" aiamm1313C, undated; aiamm1313C (Box 44, Box 65)
  - Wilson, Dick (guitar, vocals) Unidentified flute, fiddle and guitar recording session followed by concert and private performances of songs. (Length: 00:20:00) aiamm845C, undated; aiamm845C (Box 48, Box 25)
  - Zahm, Charlie (vocals, guitar) Demo. (Length: 00:10:00) aiamm846C, undated; aiamm846C (Box 48, Box 25)
  - Zahm, Charlie (vocals, guitar) Demo. (Length: 00:20:00) aiamm847C, undated; aiamm847C (Box 50, Box 25)
- Series II: Public Performances, 1965-1997, Jun 25, 1965-Feb 22, 1997
  Public Performances include concert performances, sessions, ceilis, competitions, lectures and broadcasts.
  Informal music sessions from New York, Washington DC, Cleveland, Chicago, Milwaukee, and San Francisco and many in Mick Moloney's homes in Philadelphia in the 1970s are included in this series. The earliest is a 1965 home recording from the Bronx with traditional musicians Ed Reavy, Johnny Cronin, Mike Preston, Paddy Murphy, Denis Murphy, John McMahon and J. McAulliffe. There are two rare pub session recordings from early 1976: an evening at the Bunratty in the Bronx, NY with Paddy Reynolds, Andy McGann, Johnny Cronin (fiddles), Patty Moriarty (accordion) and Mick Moloney (guitar, banjo, vocals); and one with the John Glynn Branch of the Irish Musicians Association at the Breffni Inn in Queens, New York. Glynn, an accordion player, had an influential school of music in Brooklyn at the time.
  Mick Moloney recorded the tradition as it was being taught as well as played. Tapes of Martin Mulvihill's School of Irish Music in the Bronx, Father Charlie Coen's Children's Choir on Staten Island, and the 1978 Comhaltas Ceoltóirí Éireann Fleadh Cheoil competition at Manhattan College in the Bronx (a.k.a. New York Fleadh) are included. He seized the opportunity to document young musicians who later blossomed into traditional Irish music stars, including twelve-year-old fiddler Eileen Ivers and fifteen-year-old Seamus Egan (mandolin, flute, whistle, uilleann pipes, banjo). Ivers (now a nine time All-Ireland fiddle champion) can be heard playing in 1977 with a youth ceili band for the Green Linnet album Irish Music, the Living Tradition. Egan was recorded in 1984 playing banjo at a Philadelphia session with Liz Carroll, Jimmy Keane and Mick Moloney, as well as in two pub sessions that same summer in Miltown Malbay, Co. Clare. Moloney later showcased both Ivers and Egan in his touring ensemble, Mick Moloney and Friends, and this part of the collection features many examples of their playing in the 1990s. A twenty-year old Michael Flatley was recorded playing the flute in Chicago in 1978; the following year he performed with Mick Moloney as part of the pioneering touring ensemble, The Green Fields of America.
  Concert performances include Moloney's own ensemble The Green Fields of America; the first American concerts by the Irish traditional supergroups the Chieftains (1974), De Danann (1978) and Clannad (1979); and performances at such legendary venues as the Eagle Tavern in New York City, the Cherry Tree in Philadelphia, and Godfrey Daniels in Bethlehem, PA. In 1983 Moloney helped organize the ensemble Cherish the Ladies, represented here by recordings with sean nós singers Treasa Ui Cearuil and Bridget Fitzgerald as well as by a 1988 performance in Woodside, New York during the height of undocumented immigration from Ireland. That concert featured the young Irish American musician Joanie Madden (1983 All-Ireland gold medalist on tin whistle and flute). Of particular interest is the three-hour February 1990 benefit concert for Joe Doherty, an Irish political prisoner held by American authorities while fighting extradition to the United Kingdom, which was the occasion for a historic gathering of a veritable "who's who" of Irish traditional musicians at Symphony Space in New York City. Only excerpts from this concert were included on the 1991 Green Linnet record The Rights of Man.
  Two foreign tours funded by the United States Information Agency are represented here by a September 1983 concert performance at the Hotel Ivoire, Abidjan, Cote d'Ivoire, in Africa with Mick Moloney (banjo, guitar), Liz Carroll (fiddle), Donny and Eileen Golden (dancing); and by a May 1985 concert performance at the ruins of the Grand Hotel (Casa Grande) in Managua, Nicaragua with Susie Goff and the Green Grass Cloggers, Mick Moloney (mandolin) and Robbie O'Connell (guitar, vocals). The former was part of the Festival of Traditional American Dance; the latter part of the Festival of Mountain Music and Dance.
  In 1975 Mick Moloney also began to document outdoor festivals in the United States at which Irish traditional music was featured, beginning with a concert in Philadelphia's Lenape Park that became the genesis for the Philadelphia Ceili Group Festival. The collection documents several years of this festival as well as the 1976 Smithsonian Folklife Festival, whose Irish segment was curated by Moloney. He travelled to Leeds in New York's Catskill mountains where, in 1978, he recorded Billy McComiskey (accordion), Andy McGann (fiddle), Maureen Doherty (flute) and the Clancy Brothers with Tommy Makem, among others. By the 1980s Moloney was a regular at the Cuyahoga Valley National Recreation Area in Cleveland, OH; at the Augusta Heritage Center, in Elkins, WV and at Milwaukee Irish Fest in Milwaukee, WI. All of these festivals are well documented here.
  In addition to numerous academic lectures presented by Moloney in Ireland and America, this part of the collection features many interesting Moloney-related radio broadcasts. Of particular historic interest is Across the Western Ocean: The Story of Irish Traditional Music in America, a National Public Radio series written, hosted and produced by Mick Moloney in 1978. Its thirteen episodes are a musical snapshot of Irish America in the wake of the twelve part Roots phenomenon, aired just one year earlier.
  Among items in this series inherited by Mick Moloney are tapes uilleann piper and radio host Thomas Standeven made of the John Vesey Trio in 1974. Vesey (1924-1995), one of Philadelphia's finest fiddlers in the Sligo tradition, only made private recordings between 1954 and 1974. Inherited as well is a recording made by Irish broadcaster Ciarán MacMathúna for his Sunday morning radio program Mo Cheol Thú on Radio Telefis Éireann (RTE), which captured a ceili led by Larry Redican at the Commodore Barry Club/Philadelphia Irish Center in the early 1970s. Three short interviews (two in the Irish language with recent immigrants from Falcarragh, Co. Donegal) conducted by MacMathúna can be found in this series because they precede the ceili; the one in English with Nancy McCahill concerns the creation of the Philadelphia Irish Center.
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  - Side A: Donegan, Lonnie (from original recording); Side B: Donegan, Lonnie; Bob Cort Skiffle. aiamm1252C, 1956-1957; aiamm1252C (Box 67, Box 44)